Hello English learners and welcome
to English pod, my name is Marco.
I'm Amira.
Alright, Amira is here today
and she's going to tell us
about the wonderful lesson
she has prepared this time.
Well, thank you Marco.
Well, today we have a
very interesting lesson
prepared for you, it's about
someone cutting in line.
Cutting in line, okay.
Yeah, it happens all
the time and we all get
very upset about it, but
you know, it happens.
Right, right.
Well, I imagine that everyone
is wondering what cutting in
line is, why don't we just
listen to the dialogue one time
and then when we come
back, Amira and I will
gladly explain all the
vocabulary in this dialogue.
Let's listen.
I can't believe it took
us two hours to get here.
The traffic in New York is unbelievable.
Yeah, but just relax, honey, we're
here, we're going on vacation.
In a few hours we'll be in Hawaii
and you'll be on the golf course.
I don't know, look at that line.
It must be a mile long.
There's no way I'm waiting
for another two hours.
Honey, don't.
Hey man, the end of the line is over there.
Yeah.
No, seriously, I was your first
and you can't cut in line like this.
Says who I do.
So, sue me.
All right, that's it.
Whoa, I say there's punching.
Yeah, I guess this guy was just a
crazy, I don't know, impatient man, huh?
Yes, yes, but we don't
want to talk about this now.
But for now, we will treat
some of the vocabulary
and very useful
phrases in the dialogue.
Great.
Mark, could you want to start?
Yes, let's take a look at our
first word would be unbelievable.
Unbelievable.
Exactly.
And just how you say it, it's something
incredible, something amazing.
Yeah, but I would like to point out that
unbelievable was used here to describe
the man's frustration.
He's not happy about
the traffic in New York.
Exactly, perfect.
Okay, in the next part, the woman
she's trying to calm and relax her husband,
and she says that they'll be in Hawaii in a
few hours and you'll be on the golf course.
Right, so we'll be in Hawaii
and you'll be on the golf course.
Yes, we'll be in Hawaii and
you'll be on the golf course.
So this is a great way of talking about
your physical location in the future.
Right, so for example, a mirror
tomorrow, where will you be?
Don't worry, Marko, I'll
be in the office tomorrow.
Perfect, right?
That's where I need you to be.
Yes.
Okay.
All right.
Well, I have another interesting
phrase here for you must be a mile long.
A mile long.
Now, that's basically not a mile.
It's not a kilometer
long, but it's another way
of saying that this
line is really, really long.
Right, it's just an exaggeration.
Now, let's take a look at there's no way.
There's no way.
Perfect, let's listen to some
other examples on how we use.
There's no way in a different situation.
And then we can come back
and talk about it a little bit more.
There's no way I can have
those reports finished today.
The stadium is so crowded that
there's no way we'll find a seat.
Do you think Michael's
going to buy that house?
There's no way he has
enough money to buy it.
All right, everyone.
And so there's no way is another
way of saying it is impossible.
Exactly.
There's no way you should
miss this podcast, right?
Yes.
Well, I have another
phrase for you as well.
Cut in line, cut in line,
cut in line, cut in line.
Cut in line.
So again, we have some
really good examples
on how you could use this
phrase in different situations.
Let's listen to the examples and then we
can come back and talk about it some more.
Excuse me. I'm really late.
Can I cut in line, please?
I hate it when people
cut in line at the bank.
It's so rude.
I think it's okay when a
pregnant woman cuts in line.
Alright, everyone, cut in line.
Right. So from the
examples, we can understand
that it means when
you are standing in line
somewhere and somebody
gets in front of you.
Right. I have another phrase for you here.
"Sumi." "Sumi." "Sumi." "Sumi." Okay.
Now, "Sumi" is not a nice phrase.
If you hear that, you
know you're in trouble.
Yeah, it's uh, it's kind of
rude, I guess, to say "Sumi.
" Right. Well, it actually
means like taking someone
to court and asking for
money because someone
has harmed you in a
way. I think that we should
listen to the dialogue one
more time and try to figure
out why he used that phrase and if
he's really going to take him to court.
I can't believe it took
us two hours to get here.
The traffic in New
York is unbelievable.
Yeah, but just relax honey.
We're here and we're going on vacation.
In a few hours we'll be in Hawaii
and you'll be on the golf course.
No, look at that line.
It must be a mile long.
There's no way I'm waiting
for another two hours.
Honey, don't.
Hey man, the end of the line is over there.
Yeah. No, seriously, I was your
first and you can't cut in line like this.
Says who? I do. So, "Sumi."
Alright, that's it.
Alright, we're back. Now, this guy,
when he says "Sumi," he's just being rude.
I mean, he's just being kind of
impolite and telling him, "I don't care.
" Right, exactly. Like, you
can't do anything about it.
Yeah. Okay, today in the
studio we have a guest.
Her name is Sarah
and she's from England.
Hi there. Hello. All
right, so we're going to
be asking her a couple
of questions and she'll
be a frequent guest on
our show so you can expect
to hear from her a lot.
Well, she didn't know
that. Yes, it's a
surprise. She knows now.
Well, Sarah, our topic today
is about jumping the queue.
Okay, I'm here. Oh, wait.
What is this jump the queue?
It's the same as cut in
line, but in British English.
Oh, okay. Yes, queuing.
It's very important in England.
We're very proud of our queue.
That's true, it's true.
So, so what would be
the reaction of people if
they like, you know, cut in line?
I think we do take
it very seriously.
I'm laughing now, but
it's quite a very serious.
So you don't dump the queue. If
people, you know, jump in front of you,
it's, you get a little
touch and so on.
You shouldn't, shouldn't be
doing that. And we make it
very obvious. And in the
studio loud, we would, you
know, perhaps say something
and we have systems,
you know, in London, on the
metro, on the underground,
you have to stand on
the escalators on the
right and queue and
you can't jump in front.
You have to walk on the
left and queue on the right.
There's all very serious,
there's rules and regulation.
Is there like a queue
handbook that you have
to read in high school
and kind of take a test
on? Perhaps there
should be. That should be,
yeah. What about
New York, Marco?
Well, no, definitely, I guess
this dialogue is similar to a
reality of New York. If
somebody gets in front
of you or cuts the line,
somebody's going to say
something and probably end
up in a fight if the guy is rude.
Yeah. Oh my God.
Yeah. Well, Sarah,
why don't you tell us, is there a line or a
queue for almost everything in England?
It seems like we do
just like to form a queue.
Yeah. So, yeah. Can you
think of like some other
examples of where you
would normally you wouldn't
queue, but you do? Oh,
gosh. Um, things like in
the supermarket, when
you're trying to find
some vegetable or
something, I'd never push,
I'd never sort of reach
around or anything.
I'd just wait until that
person had finished picking
up their stuff and
then, and then go in.
So, just try and... So, I have
like five people want to buy
oranges at the supermarket,
then you have a little
mini queue of
five people waiting.
There's no sort of just
shoving through it to the front.
You just don't do that. So,
you don't stick your hand
out and grab like a
tomato. Well, if you do,
again, you would make
sure that that person knows,
oh, I'm sorry, I'm just
in a hurry or whatever,
but yeah, it's just letting
someone go before you,
it's a courtesy, I think. Okay.
It's quite important to us.
All right. Great. Thank
you so much, Sarah.
Pleasure. Yeah, we'll
have you back very soon.
So, all right, we're at a
time, but we'll be back
tomorrow with another
lesson, and be sure to visit
our website, don't
forget that englishpot.
com has many, many
resources and also a community
of users and teachers that can help you
answer questions and interact with you.
Yes, and you should definitely
leave your suggestions,
but for now, I wish you all well, and bye.